Register of the Paul Myron Anthony Linebarger Papers, 1922-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1922-1965. (Box No. 19-31.)
  - Nuclear war. Recuperative capacity (Folder 8)
  - Philippine Islands (Folder 9)
    - "Foreign Trade Statistics of the Philippines", 1960
    - Population and housing reports, 1960
    - Report on Mauban, Quezon, 1953
    - Review of The Philippines, A Study in National Development by Joseph R. Hayden, 1942
  - Prisoners of war, German. Reports from the Office of the Provost Marshal General, Prisoner of War, Special Projects Division, Washington, D.C., 1946 (Folder 10)
  - Psychological warfare (Box 29.)
    - General
      - Bibliographies (Folder 1)
      - Clippings (Folder 2)
      - Notes (Folder 3)
    - Area handbooks. Memoranda and notes, February, 1956 (Folder 4)
    - Cold War strategy. Report by William A. Lybrand, February, 1962 (Folder 5)
    - Communist. "Communist Interrogation and Indoctrination of 'Enemies of the State'" by Lawrence E. Hinkle, Jr., M.D. and Harold G. Wolff, M.D., 1956 (Folder 6)
    - Department of the Army (Folder 7)
      - Office of the Chief of Psychological Warfare, Organization charts
      - Strategic Intelligence Symposium, December, 1961
    - Korean War. Battle bulletins, 1952 (Folder 8)
    - Miscellany (Folder 9)
    - Psychological operations
      - Department of the Army Field Manual, 1962 (Folder 10)
      - "Psychological Operations Equipment", by Harold M.Coter, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - The Psywar Society. Bulletins, 1958, 1959, 1961, 1965 (incomplete) (Folder 12)
    - Special Operations Research Office. Notes for reviews and for counterinsurgency articles, 1963 (Folder 13)
    - "The Theory and Practice of Psychological Warfare" by Wong T'se-shing and Chen Ying-leu, 1952 (Folder 14)
    - U.S. Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948. Reprint (Folder 15)
    - Voice of America. Clipping, April 22, 1947 (Folder 16)
    - World War I. Report (incomplete) (Folder 17)
    - World War II - Japanese propaganda. "The Secret of Psychological Warfare" by Suma Yakichiro (Folder 18)
  - Religion (Box 30., Folder 1)
    - "The Faith of Great Scientists", 1948
    - "My Faith" by Barley Willis
    - "The Upper Room", 1952
  - Republic of China (Taiwan)
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Chiang Kai-shek, Mme. Notes on meeting with Mme. Chiang, August 14, 1962 (Folder 3)
    - Communism. "The Doom of Communism", speech by Chiang Kai-shek, 1963 (Folder 4)
    - Constitution. (Folder 5)
      - "The Constitution of the Kuomintang", 1957
      - "The Main Features of the Permanent Constitution of the Republic of China" by Tsao Wen-yen, 1953
    - Economic conditions (Folder 6)
      - "Economic Development Planning in Taiwan" by Ralph J. Watkins, report prepared for Agency for International Development, Department of State, ca. 1961
      - "Economic Miracle in Free China", illustrated booklet, 1962
      - "My Views on Taiwan's Economy" by K.Y. Yin, 1953
    - Foreign relations
      - General. "So I Tell the American People" by Kwei Chungshu, 1953 (Folder 7)
      - Australia. "Programme of the Visit to the Republic of China of the Australian Goodwill Mission", August 8-17, 1956 (Folder 8)
    - Land reform. "Land Reform in Free China", 1953 (Folder 9)
    - Politics and government. Organization charts of government officials and Kuomingtang leaders in English and Chinese, 1962 (Folder 10)
    - Religion (Folder 11)
      - "Selected Speeches on Religion by President and Mme. Chiang Kai-shek", 1952
      - "Stranger Than Fiction" by James Dickson, n.d.
      - "Testimony on Good Friday" by President Chiang Kai-shek and "Easter Meditation" by Mme. Chiang Kai-shek, 1956
    - Women. "The Position of Women in Free China", by Hsu Chung-pei, 1953 (Folder 12)
  - School of Advanced International Studies, The Johns Hopkins University. Course outlines, examinations, seminar topics, staff directory (Folder 13)
  - Science fiction (Folder 14)
    - "An Adventure in Venus"
    - "The Elixir"
    - "The Girl From Mars"
    - "The Thought Stealer and the Mechanical Man"
    - "The Thought Translator and the Creation"
    - "The Vanguard of Venus"
    - "When the Moon Fell"
  - Southeast Asia. "Countries of Asia. Burma and Indonesia" published in Moscow, 1955 (in Russian) (Folder 15)
  - Thailand. Press summary on revision of Nationality Act, 1963 (Folder 16)
  - U Thant. Biographical sketch (Box 31., Folder 1)
  - Unemployment. Hearings Before a Subcommittee of the Committee on Labor, House of Representatives, 1932 (Folder 2)
  - U.S.S.R. (Folder 3)
    - "A Report on Russian Destruction of Our Industries in the North-eastern Provinces", 1952
    - "Soviet Political Treaties and Violations" Staff Study for the Subcommittee to Investigate the Administration of the Internal Security Act... U.S. Senate, 1955
    - "Vostok" by Alexander Pronin, report on Soviet counterinsurgency, n.d.
  - United Nations. Speech by Joseph C. Grew on the founding of the United Nations, April 29, 1945 (Folder 4)
  - United States
    - Army officers. Memoir, 1923-1944 (Folder 5)
    - Department of Health, Education and Welfare - Clippings (Folder 6)
    - Foreign relations
      - Asia. "Draft Statement of a Ten-Year China and Indochina Policy, 1956-1966", 1956 (Folder 7)
      - Laos. "First Americans Up the Mekong" by MacAllister (?), 1961 (Folder 8)
      - Southeast Asia. "Southeast Asia as a Problem Area in the Next Decade", address given by Dr. Guy J. Pauker, October 6, 1958 (Folder 9)
    - Office of War Information. Organization charts (Folder 10)
  - Vietnam. "Government and Administration in Viet-Nam", n.d. (Folder 11)
  - Vosnjak, Bogumil. Curriculum vitae (Folder 12)
  - World calendar. "A Symposium on the World Calendar", 1951 (Folder 13)
  - World government. "How to Prevent Warfare and Establish Foundation of World Unity" by Yen Hsi-shan, 1952 (Folder 14)
  - World War II (Folder 15)
    - Hammond's War Map of Europe
    - "World War II Strategy and Its Significance Today" speech by Gen. Albert C. Wedemeyer (?), n.d
- Microfilm, 1942-1949. (Microfilm Cabinets)
  Seven reels of microfilm of papers of Paul Myron Anthony Linebarger. Originals are in the Hitotsubashi University Library, Tokyo.
  - Personal Files on the Far East. Memoranda, meeting notes, reports, correspondence relating to Sino-American relations, American aid, psychological warfare plans for China, February, 1942 -November, 1942. Including memoranda to William Donovan, Lauchlin Currie, Archibald MacLeish. (Reel I.)
  - Memoranda, correspondence, October, 1942 -May, 1943. Including memoranda to Lauchlin Currie and Owen Lattimore. (On June 30, 1943, Linebarger left for the China-Burma-India Theater of World War II. His records for this period are not on this microfilm. The material resumes again when he returned to his duties in the Pentagon's Propaganda Branch, G-2, March, 1945) (Reel II.)
  - Diary notes, correspondence, memoranda, including a message to General Albert C. Wedemeyer, January 17, 1946, and from Wedemeyer, September 13, 1949, material on postwar planning, the dropping of the atomic bombs on Japan, a report on the Japanese Emperor, a memorandum to General Douglas MacArthur, a letter of commendation from General George C. Marshall to Elmer Davis, Head of the Office of War Information, correspondence with John Carter Vincent, report entitled "Organization and Functions of the Office of International Information and Cultural Affairs", December 20, 1945, and the Directory of the Military Intelligence Division, January 15, 1946 (Reel III.)
  - Papers Prepared by Paul Myron Linebarger, September, 1942 -December, 1942, for Joseph C. Grew, American Ambassador to Japan, 1931-1941, miscellaneous correspondence (Reel IV.)
  - Papers Prepared for Joseph Grew, January -May, 1943. Memorandum of Linebarger conversation with Grew, May 13, 1943 (Reel V.)
  - Papers Prepared for Joseph Grew, June, 1943. Miscellaneous correspondence and memoranda (Reel VI.)
  - Correspondence of Linebarger and Grew, March, 1944 -January, 1946, correspondence from General Wedemeyer, 1945. Organization Chart entitled "Plans and Operations Division, GSUSA", June 30, 1948, "Appendix III" (l page) on the Cold War, n.d. (Reel VII.)
- AUDIO-VISUAL., (87 prints / 58 postcards / 2 albums (circa 1931) / 3 recordings / 5 negatives
  - 16 prints of Paul M.A. Linebarger and family; 3 unidentified prints; 1 print of the Eiffel Tower; 1 slide; 5 negatives; 58 postcards, undated (Folder A)
  - 30 prints of Japanese prisoner of war camp, Camp McCoy, Wisconsin, World War II; 26 prints of China, World War II; 2 prints of Djang Chu; 9 unidentified prints, undated (Box B)